LAUGHING MAN FANSUBS
Motoko!
If one's physical body is lost, can a person's mind traverse the net,
while maintaining its existence and individual identity?
Who knows?
It is difficult to believe that unified consciousness can be maintained in the "sea" that is the net, after having lost its shell.
Would this world then be despair itself for those who lose their identities, even as they live?
That depends on what exactly you consider to be despair.
They might as well try dying in that case, don't you think?
That could be a possibility.
In the meantime, I would like to express my gratitude.
Thank you.
The way in which you kept your promise was...
exceptionally charming.
Public Safety
Section 9
Once Again
"Convenient rationales such as "teamwork" do not exist among us."
"All that is necessary is teamwork that arises from the actions of individuals."
This was the Chief's admonition to us, when Section 9 was first created.
Did the Chief really abandon us?
I was subjected to useless interrogation,
and I was unable to communicate with my co-workers
or obtain external information.
And then, fifteen days later, I was suddenly released.
The notification that they handed me upon my release
included information detailing Section 9's dissolution
and orders  to go on indefinite furlough from the security company
with which I was officially employed until then.
However, from where was the notification I was waiting for to come?
RECEPTION
I scrambled in the hopes of
somehow obtaining information
concerning what had happened
during my detention.
243 Ruling Party Candidates
in Lower House Elections
DO NOT ENTER / NIIHAMA PREFECTURAL POLICE / DO NOT ENTER
OPEN 24H
6F NET CAFE
Welcome to Cyber Plaza Central
Please Wait
Several Public Safety Members
Charged with Treason against the State!!
A plan by radical Public Safety members to start a military uprising was uncovered.
That was the "truth" that had been disclosed to the general public.
Most of the media portrayed the use of force by a self-defence army,
which was said to have been deployed to preempt a coup d'etat, in a favorable light.
Section 9 members, who were charged with treason as central figures in the plot,
were detained, arrested and prosecuted by the military.
Summary judgement was handed down rapidly.
However, the fate of my friends was classified, the media was censored,
and I could do nothing, as I had become a civilian.
However, two things remained that still did not add up.
The first was that Section 9's central figure, the Chief
, had completely disappeared from the political scene.
His name did not appear on journal articles,
nor was it exposed in the list of casualties.
Had he actually abandoned us?
And, one more thing; the Major, the only member whose fate had been announced...
Could the Major really be dead?
Three months have passed.
At times, fulfilling one's duties as a member of Public Safety
is a task that requires a will capable of enduring seemingly endless investigations.
However, I had never felt it to be an unbearable pain.
Still, why is it that I am allowed to live as if nothing
has happened, while time continues to tick on by?
I felt oppressed by the days spent as an unemployed
husband and father to my family. It pained me greatly.
I guess it's about time for me to find a new job.
Secretary General Yakushima Rejects Request for Party Withdrawal
Prosecution to Investigate Party Headquarters
We have heard that the prosecution is about to arrive.
Many reporters are gathered at the party's headquarters today,
and the atmosphere is quite somber.
The Ministry of Public Health, Labour, and Welfare's
involvement with Serano Genomix Corporation, which
was covered in tabloids prior to the Lower House
elections, has entangled Secretary General Yakushima.
And now, a week after the new cabinet was installed,
the case has finally developed into a full-fledged inquiry.
The prosecution is conducting a thorough probe at the party's headquarters...
Hey, he's here!
An in-depth investigation has finally begun; will Yakushima be arrested by day's end?
Are the rumored Serano stocks stored within this building?
Live Coverage of the Investigation
at Ruling Party HQ
We have credible information.
We will most likely request that the Secretary General come in voluntarily for questioning.
What of the possibility that the cash with recorded serial
numbers mentioned in Mr. Serano's testimony is stored here?
The probe will reveal that as well.
We have been investigating diligently in preparation for Secretary General Yakushima's arrest.
"Diligently", did he say?!
I don't know how the prosecution managed to assemble this much evidence,
but the information that was leaked to tabloids and personal websites
was clearly information that we uncovered,
not to mention that Section 9 also initially investigated Serano Corporation's cash flow.
Our mission will certainly be fulfilled if Yakushima is arrested.
Who actually arrests him is of little consequence.
And yet... what is this that I feel?
Their proud attitude...
Even the pristine whiteness of their shirts pisses me off.
Is this what I want?
Isn't the scenario that the Major
and the others pieced together
the truth behind the Laughing
Man Case from six years ago?
Even if the prosecution unveils the graft scandal in the Ministry of Public Health, Labour and Welfare,
Yakushima may still not retire from his post.
How is that going to significantly change anything in the world?
It's not as if I wanted to be a hero.
However, I think I've been flawless in my pursuit of what we perceived justice to be so far.
Laughing Man... you were the one who tried to shed light on this case in the first place.
Could it be that you feel the same way I do right now?
No, it can't be...
The Catcher in the Rye
J.D. Salinger
You're not one to object to such things.
You've realised something, and you're watching this from on high.
Isn't that right?
I can tell.
Major...
If I'm right about what I think will happen...
Don't move!
Take your hands out of your pockets slowly, and turn around.
With your skills, you'd be caught before you even get close to Yakushima.
But...
You're an idiot. You know that?
Come with me.
Here he is!
Took you a while.
Well? How far did you tail him?
He went to the party headquarters, just as I thought.
Are you serious?
What's wrong? You crying, or what?
Of course not!
So, how are things going?
It seems the Secretary General has finally given in.
He was affiliated with the military, after all;
he will apparently acquiesce willingly to the investigations.
With this success, the prosecution will be heroes for a while.
No doubt.
But, are you guys happy with this?
The ones who actually cornered Yakushima are...
Us in Section 9, you mean?
Well, not that I don't understand how you feel,
but all this happened according to a plan that hairy monkey-man set up, from the very beginning.
Plan?
Right.
Monkey-man realised that the Prime Minister would refrain from ousting the Secretary General
since the Lower House elections were approaching.
So, he deliberately chose to turn Section 9 into a scapegoat.
When the Major disguised herself as the Laughing Man and extracted the truth from Serano,
Section 9's existence was leaked to the media
and we were no longer able to carry out covert operations like before.
So, the Chief then negotiated with the Prime Minister
to "sacrifice" Section 9, and nudge the prosecution into action.
"Sacrifice" Section 9...
Still, do you even know how I felt during the past three months...?
Don't be so bitter. Think of it as having been on a special vacation.
It's not as if we were told of the plan beforehand, either.
The old man had faith that we would survive and gather once again,
and executed the plan with a heavy heart.
Even having you arrested and detained first
was a strategy on his part, since he wanted you to survive the raid on Section 9.
After all, you only had a few cybernetic parts, and were recovering from injuries.
Besides, as a married man, it would have been difficult to manipulate your personal information,
so there was a need to distance you from Section 9, until preparations were complete.
Don't be so negative about it.
As for me, the records still show that I'm incarcerated in Abashiri.
Swallow your pride and go for results.
With this, we have returned to being a bona fide offensive organisation that does not exist.
I see...
But still, what about the Major...?
Who knows?
I wouldn't know anything about someone like her.
Come to think of it, weren't you really crying that time, Batou?
Shut up.
Oh, yeah? Why don't I bring up footage from the satellite?
I'll send it on to the Major, too.
H-Hey, don't!
"MOTOKOOO", right?
You bastard!
I told you to stop that, bastard!
Stop it already!
So it's finished, isn't it?
Yes.
The rest will be entrusted to the judicial system.
My task is completed.
Thanks to you, the prosecution will be able to stand proud before the people.
However, what remains for you?
I was able to achieve justice, as I see it.
That is enough.
And?
What are you going to do from now on?
You can't be involved in all that gunplay forever.
How about it?
Why don't you come join us?
I've been thinking for a while that you are suited for the judicial bench.
I wonder.
Section 9 is not so easily finished.
I now intend to go recruit a new member, as a step towards reconstruction.
Oh?
Library
Museum
I see...
Not the Laughing Man, indeed.
Welcome.
You are later than I had expected you to be.
Look who's talking.
You didn't even send over an invitation.
"If you stay put, people will come to you."
Were those Doisneau's words?
Yes.
Well, the fact that I have no idea what to do with you did have something to do with my coming here as well.
As for me, I actually became a bit concerned as to whether you would die after that.
I haven't reached a point where I expect that much out of death.
Although I had a near-death experience from the shock
of having my remote body's cyberbrain destroyed.
And, having destroyed your brand-new body, you still haven't transferred into a new prosthetic yet.
A keen observation.
Peeking is my hobby.
All that aside, what is this place?
It seems like a graveyard of information.
Did you really aim to change the world from here?
Well, to a certain extent in the beginning, yes.
And? How do you feel now?
Nothing special comes to mind.
Perhaps it was already over for me when I shared my memories with you.
I thought then that you would take care of the rest...
Well, well. You are quite the liar.
"Please don't interfere..." Yeah, right.
I'm sorry.
However, upon sharing and synchronisation, all information loses its singularity
and insinuates itself into the subconscious of those who do not have an ulterior motive
or is internalized by the consciousness of those who do have an ulterior motive.
Are those your owns words, based on experience?
Yes.
After all, even you were acting as the Laughing Man in the end.
The phenomenon was indeed interesting.
That aside, what was your initial motive, the one that triggered all these incidents?
"To you, everything that occurs in the world must appear false."
J.D. Salinger.
Yes.
Well, I am the epitome of cybernetic brain and body modification.
So, I may have felt something like terror at the thought of becoming afflicted with cyberbrain sclerosis.
It all started when I chanced upon an e-mail on the net.
The email was most probably a threat addressed to Serano Genomix.
it contained an argument that was based on the comparison between an investigation of
the Serano made micromachine treatment's ineffectiveness and the Murai vaccine's effectiveness.
And the one who wrote it was the "original" Laughing Man?
When it comes down to it, yes.
"I am a machine that exists in order to show my world to everyone."
Dziga Vertov. A film director, was it?
Yes.
I imagined that my mission was
to confirm and transmit the
"information" that I chanced
upon, and exerted myself alone.
And you suffered a spectacular defeat.
The innocent mediator became dejected at the sheer odiousness of the societal system and became mute.
Yes.
And I became a mediator fated to disappear,
as if I was a writer whose existence was made all the more conspicuous because he did not publish new works.
In other words, "it is the medium that determines the societal system's dynamics via self-extermination;
when the medium disappears; it leaves its trace neither within nor without the system."
Frederic Jameson.
Yes, and no;
the latter portion is Oosawa Masachi.
Although I understood his writing, I did not believe them until I saw it with my own eyes.
To think that the absence of an original could spawn copies without an original...
If it were up to you, what would you call that phenomenon?
Standalone Complex.
Yes.
Standalone Complex...
Contrary to what one might think,
the current societal system
possesses an inherent mechanism
for triggering such phenomena.
That only feels like the beginning of despair to me...
What do you think?
Who knows?
I can't quite say.
However, I have found something that
creates the possibility of regaining
one's individuality at the end of
the synchronisation of information.
And, that is...?
Curiosity, probably.
I see.
I didn't think of that myself.
My brain must already be undergoing sclerosis...
So, what's going to happen to me?
Will I get arrested for kidnapping?
Or, is my crime acting as the instigator of multiple, simultaneous acts of terrorism?
Who knows?
I've entrusted the decision to him,
so why don't you ask him directly?
I've been listening, but that was a conversation that would have
been impossible to follow without an external memory device.
Have you read all the books here?
Not quite.
Allow me to introduce him to you.
He is my Chief, the leader of Section 9, Aramaki Daisuke.
Pleased to meet you.
Do you intend to continue with he mundane task of preserving published material,
which only exists because of tradition?
If that is permitted, yes.
In this case, it will be decided in a court of law that the original Laughing Man never existed.
With that in mind, I have a suggestion.
How about this?
Why don't you put your hacking abilities to good use as the ninth member in Section 9?
Well, you've surprised me.
You intend to recruit me?
That's right.
How interesting.
It does seem like it could be fun,
but I think I'll decline your offer.
Unfortunately, I don't play baseball well at all.
Looks like we've been rejected.
What now?
Nothing.
As long as people like you and I wish it,
Section 9 will remain an offensive organisation against crime.
That is all.
Mr. President, we finally have the first hearing today.
Yes.
With this, I can finally fulfil my promise to him.
Oh, don't bother.
One cannot survive by holding to his morals in this day and age.
Let there be peaceful slumber for the righteous ones.
Major, summon all the members in A-2 gear!
Did you get that, Batou?
Came to pick you up.
Togusa.
On my way.
Ishikawa. Saitou.
I will rendezvous with the rest via a different route.
The preparations are complete.
Pazu. Bomer!
Ready when you are!
Gotta hit the jackpot every once in a while...